Pavan Mistry

121-10 Garfella Dr, Toronto, ON, Canada

(289)-887-9438 | pavanmistry.me | linkedin.com/in/pavan1003 | pavandm.03@gmail.com

Summary

Over 1.5 years of experience in full stack application development using diverse technologies, with strong client interaction skills and a deep understanding of business applications, data flows, and data relationships, resulting in a 20% increase in client satisfaction and retention.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, Python, HTML, CSS, PHP, C++.

Script Languages/Libraries: Vue.js, Vuex, Node.js, React, Redux, React Native, TensorFlow.

Frameworks: Vite.js, Next.js, Jest, Vitest, Express.js, Laravel, Asp.net.

Software Development Tools: Git, Docker, Asana, Unfuddle.

Databases: Firebase, My SQL, Mongo.

Other: Postman, Amazon Web Services (AWS) EC2, S3, API Gateway, Cognito, IAM, Google Cloud Platform

(GCP), Cloud functions, Pub/Sub, Kubernetes, Virtual Machines.

Experience

Freelance Full Stack developer at ZioTag Inc., New York, USA

May 2024 – Present

- Followed Agile Software Development Methodology, leading to a 20% increase in project delivery efficiency.
- Consulted on and modified existing services to integrate OpenAI chat completions API, improving response accuracy by 50%.

Freelance Full Stack developer at Pangeon Inc., Spokane, USA

Feb 2024 – Present

- Integrated Stripe API payment flows, reducing payment processing time by 30% and enhancing transaction security, resulting in a 15% increase in user satisfaction ratings.
- Implemented use-case specific IAM roles for invoking AWS services in Front-end and Back-end to improve 50% of application security.

Full Stack Software Engineer at NetWeb Software, Vadodara, India

Jan 2023 – Dec 2023

- Promoted from intern to Software Engineer after 1 month, demonstrating rapid learning and proficiency.
- Created an admin panel component to track billing cycles, monitor API usage, and manage 3rd party tasks, improving operational efficiency by 25%.
- Developed major application components using Node.js, reducing bugs by 15% and enhancing system stability.

Education

Web Development – Humber College, Toronto
Information Technology – Navrachana University, Vadodara

Jan 2024 – Present

Jul 2019 – Jun 2023

Certifications

- Cisco Cybersecurity Essentials.
- Fundamentals of Digital Marketing from Google Digital Garage.
- Learn to code using Python 3 from Udemy.